

■ joey.mckenzie27@gmail.com | 🌴 joeymckenzie.tech | 🖸 JoeyMcKenzie | 🛅 JoeyMcKenzie | 💆 joeyMcKenzie | 🍎 the_beercoder

Summary.

Seasoned professional software developer with diverse experience building enterprise-grade distributed software systems with technologies in .NET, Java, and TypeScript across industries including healthcare, insurance, manufacturing, and fintech. I specialize in building fast, efficient cloud-based web services and APIs with AWS and Azure alongside modern web applications with Angular, React, and Vue. I have a passion for software architecture and design, software leadership and mentorship, and delivering high-quality software products at a nationwide scale.

I am an avid contributor to open source, primarily in the Rust and TypeScript ecosystems, alongside minor contributions in Go with community projects hosted across GitHub, Vercel and Netlify. I enjoy dispersing knowledge and experience with other like-minded developers sharing a similar passion for software development and design. I write and produce technical content on my blog, Twitch, and YouTube exploring emerging technologies with a focus on developer advocacy.

Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

National Funding

· Developing .NET microservices, React applications with Next.js, and AWS infrastructure supporting financial operations

- Migrating legacy services to serverless architectures with AWS Lambda, API Gateway, S3, and SQS
- Integrating with **Plaid** products in **Link** into financial services for gathering user transaction and asset data
- Managing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with AWS, Terraform, Jenkins, and containerized workflows with Docker
- Upgrading internal .NET infrastructure improving performance and speed by 25% while reducing AWS costs
- Troubleshooting applications errors using log aggregation services with OpenSearch and Kibana
- Maintaining company-wide build artifacts with **NuGet** and source code with **GitHub**
- · Participating in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

MediKeeper Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec 2020 - Jan 2022

- Developed .NET and JavaScript applications with Vue deployed to Azure infrastructure
- · Worked with product teams and UX designers to compose Sass and Material Design-based UIs with Figma
- Migrated existing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes to Azure DevOps to improve existing build times
- Administered SQL Server and Oracle databases while improving business critical query times by up to 35%
- · Improved existing system architecture by migrating legacy .NET Framework applications to modern .NET
- · Maintained integration suites with JavaScript and Cypress to automate platform testing, increasing QA velocity by 20%
- · Participated in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

Sierra Pacific Industries Redding, CA

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Developed internal applications and dashboards using modern RPG ILE on the IBM iSeries AS/400 and .NET for desktop applications
- Migrated brownfield and legacy applications to modern RPG architectures increasing application response times
- Improved business critical PL/SQL queries for embedded systems by up to 40% in several applications
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with RDi, Azure DevOps, and VSTS
- · Managed database schemas with SQL Server using SSMS to support inventory management operations

VSP Global Sacramento, CA

• Developed Java APIs and Angular applications with TypeScript deployed to AWS hosting infrastructure

- Migrated legacy JEE and Spring applications to Spring Boot while increasing response times by up to 25%
- · Lead development of Angular applications utilizing Material Design, Sass, RxJS, NgRx, and modern web standards · Created and maintained CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins, Chef, and containterized workflows with Docker
- Administrated systems and servers while migrating non-production workloads off legacy Windows servers to Linux servers
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with Artifcatory and source code with BitBucket
- Assisted in troubleshooting company-wide service outages and application performance issues with Splunk and Wily
- · Participated in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

Engility Corporation San Diego, CA

- · Wrote and maintained VBA and R codebases to perform data analysis and spreadsheet specific functionality
- Provided contractor support for U.S. Department of Defense naval programs for systems engineering and data analysis
- · Performed regression analysis and statistical programming using R to refine estimated financial expenditure models
- · Managed automated Excel spreadsheets and codebases in RStudio for data analysis and exploration
- Maintained databases of financial data and provided ad hoc SQL reporting for various projects

Education

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST

San Diego State University

Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2020

Sept. 2016 - May 2018

Jan. 2022 - Present